Stephen G Collins

3601 Kernan Blvd S, Jacksonville, FL 32224 (904) 438-9199

sgcollins@outlook.com
https://nibblesnbits.net/

FULL-STACK WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

Over ten years of successful software development experience with a reputation for meeting the most challenging organizational goals and objectives. A pragmatic and focused individual recognized for "making seemingly impossible situations work." A proven and verifiable record for:

- Producing higher performance standards and enhancing productivity during a period of shrinking budgets.
- Streamlining processes—constantly analyzing and reassessing existing methods to improve overall output
- Controlling growth management—able to motivate and maximize productivity and employee morale without financial incentives.
- Developing and implementing highly successful strategic plans (short and long term).
- Maintaining up-to-date knowledge of every aspect of an organization—beyond the immediate job requirements.

Professional Experience	Concurrent Projects
Guidewell/Florida Blue, Nov 2019 – Present	Ostrich, Oct 2020 – Present
	https://getostrich.com/
SENIOR DEVELOPER – Responsible for the development and maintenance of health plan management systems serving millions of customers across the country.	CONSULTING DEVELOPER – Responsible for the entire design and development process of retail inventory management system.
Specific duties and responsibilities include:	
 Design, develop, and maintain both front and back- end applications using Node.js and React 	Utilized multiple development technologies such as Node.js , Express.js , React , Relay , GraphQL , Material-UI
 Develop proof-of-concept products using React with both GraphQL and REST APIs 	Utilized Azure-based technologies such as App Services, Azure SQL, Azure DNS, and Application Insights
ASG Results/National Auto Care, Mar 2019 – Oct 2019	Gomigo, LLC, Oct 2019 – Present https://gomigo.app/
SENIOR DEVELOPER – Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of vehicle service contract issuance site used by over 100 credit unions across the	LEAD DEVELOPER – Responsible for the entire design and development process of a social scheduling application.
country. Specific duties and responsibilities include:	Utilized multiple development technologies such as Node.js, Express.js, and React Utilized Azure-based technologies such as App Services, Azure SQL, MongoDB, Azure DNS, Azure Active Directory, Function Apps, Front Door, Azure CDN, Ke Vault, Azure Cache for Redis, and Blob Storage
 Design, develop, and maintain both front and back- end applications using C#, and ASP.NET MVC 5 	
 Develop proof-of-concept products using C#, .NET Core, React and Azure 	
Fidelity National Financial, Mar 2018 – Mar 2019	ECP, Inc. July 2018 – Present https://ecpinc.net/
SENIOR DEVELOPER – Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of multiple enterprise-scale systems responsible for processing over \$4 billion per year in Title and Escrow polices and fees.	CONSULTING DEVELOPER – Responsible for the entire design and development process of a customer claim reporting system.

Utilized multiple technologies such as SQLite, jQuery, React,

Utilized Azure DevOps for CI/CD process deploying to

C#, and .NET Core

other hosted services

in Title and Escrow polices and fees.

Specific duties and responsibilities include:

Design, develop, and maintain both front and backend applications using C#, jQuery, ASP.NET MVC and Web API hosted partially in Azure

- · Document new and existing systems
- Manage remediation of application security analysis findings

Centeva, LLC, Aug 2016 – Feb 2018

SENIOR DEVELOPER – Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of an n-tier Government Acquisitions Management system.

Specific duties and responsibilities include:

- · Design, develop, and maintain both front and back-end systems for Government Acquisitions Management
- Integrating existing systems with third-party services
- Produce custom developer tooling for back-end systems management

PROJECTS

Enterprise Service Bus for Department of Veterans Affairs:

Placed in charge of development for existing .NET 4.5 and SQL Server 2012 ESB, providing APIs and services for a
host of client applications

Client-facing Acquisitions Management applications:

- · Assisted in development of custom developed front-end for Acquisitions Management
 - o Inherited and maintained existing software from previous contracting customer
 - Revamped React/Redux-based existing UI and Web API 2 server functionality, resulting in 5-star ratings from government clients all over the country.

Glimpse Live, LLC, 2015 - 2016

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER – Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of an n-tier Optometry and Dentistry business analytics platform.

Specific duties and responsibilities include:

- Spearheaded the design and development of full backend powering a modern client data extraction and analytics system
- Produced custom **developer tooling** for arbitrarily structured data analysis
- Gained skills in Agile development practices utilizing Atlassian JIRA software
- Utilized various Linux distributions within local VMs and AWS EC2 instances
- Managed Node.js application deployment with pm2 and nginx

COMPLETED PROJECTS

Dentistry Business Analytics platform:

- Worked mostly unaided in development of all aspects of a fully custom business analytics platform.
 - O Designed MongoDB 2.6 and SQL Server 2014 underlying databases
 - Architected a Redis-based queue processing system for data transformation and analytics
 - Wrote custom queries and stored procedures for various CRUD operations
 - Developed front and back-end JavaScript and Typescript for client UI utilizing React, MongoDB, Express.js, and Node.js
 - Created and consumed JSON web services with Express.js and ASP.NET Web API
- Created and maintained .NET 4.5 client applications for data extraction

Optometry Business Analytics platform:

- Teamed up with developers and subject matter experts to create new revisions of Optometry EHR system data extraction services
 - Developed from-scratch .NET 4.5 multithreaded data extraction service
 - o Performed maintenance on existing .NET 3.5 services

RR Donnelley & Sons Company, 2012 - 2015

WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER - Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of over 50 individual client web sites, both back-end and front-end for a range of large financial institutions including T. Rowe Price and Washington Mutual.

Specific duties and responsibilities include:

- · Worked with development team to create new ASP.NET sites based on client requirements
 - Developed new applications in both ASP.NET WebForms and MVC platforms
 - 0 Utilized both ADO.NET and Entity Framework for data access to a SQL Server 2008 database
 - Wrote custom queries and stored procedures for various CRUD operations \circ
 - Developed font-ends using HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, and Bootstrap
 - Created and consumed web services with both WCF and Web API
- · Maintained existing client sites, providing new and updated features as requested
- Developed new, fully customized internal reporting tools
 - Developed fully custom server and client-side UI controls
- · Maintained up-to-date skills in new and emerging technologies
 - Gained knowledge in many server-side JavaScript products such as Node.js and MongoDB

United States Air Force, 2008 – 2012

AEROSPACE PROPULSION JOURNEYMAN - Completed 4-year career with the U.S. Air Force. Gained management status above peers. Participated in the complete revitalization and overhaul of the EC-130H weapons system from the low status perceived in the past to the most powerful and effective Electronic Combat platform in history.

An active participant in the multiple cross-service contingency preparation exercises, and served a tour supporting combat missions in Operation Enduring Freedom. Part of a team that, during my service, received multiple servicelevel awards, including the Air Combat Command Maintenance Effectiveness award 3 consecutive years. A successful record for managing complex operations, supervising teams of people responsible for \$2.2 billion in assets.

Precision Castparts Corporation, May - December 2007

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (Temporary Co-op) - Maintained and developed Enterprise Resource Planning software managing \$300 million of inventory per year utilizing a SQL Server 2000/2005 and FoxPro-based backend, with Visual Basic 6 and C# 2.0 client and server-side applications. Responsible for "modernization" of ERP system by migrating existing client-side applications to .NET standards and architecture. Specific duties and responsibilities include:

- · Worked in three-man team in the development and maintenance of a VB6/FoxPro/SQL Server 2000-based **ERP** system for a major aeronautics industry parts manufacturer.
 - Solely responsible for upgrading existing VB6 and FoxPro application to .NET (C# and VB)
- Assisted team in implementation and integration of new VB6/SQL Server 2005-based ERP system by modifying existing applications as well as developing utilities for data migration.
- Proposed and subsequently assigned with setup/maintenance of new development environment
 - Performed setup and configuration (hardware and software) of source repository, file server, Exchange accounts for development/testing use, and isolated SQL Server instance
 - Developed bug reporting library and associated application

Stephen Glynn Collins -- (904) 438-9199 -- sgcollins@outlook.com

Additional Skills

Windows software development and testing with multiple languages and environments:

- · Nearly 20 years experience with Microsoft Visual Studio using VB.NET and C#
- 10 years experience in multiple web platform technologies including:
 - ASP.NET WebForms, Web API, and MVC
 - o Node.js with Express.js and other libraries
 - Multiple front-end development tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and a wealth of libraries.
- Experience with multiple .NET libraries and conventions: Windows Forms, ADO.NET, LINQ, Generics, TPL, and Visual Studio Tools for Office.
- Knowledge and experience with industry standard patterns & practices

Experience in SQL Server 2000 through 2016 setup and deployment

- · Contributed to implementation of large-scale ERP system
- Expertise in T-SQL and normalized database design

Skilled in presenting clear and concise training

• Conducted several training courses in classroom and on-the-job settings in 10+ subjects

Education

DeVry University Online - Game and Simulation Programming

- Pursued Bachelors in Applied Science.
- Maintained 3.6 GPA over 2 semesters; placed on DeVry University Dean's List both terms.

Community College of the Air Force - Aviation Maintenance Technology

• Completed 39 credit hours towards associate's degree during time in service; continued education with DeVry University.

East Central Technical College - Game and Simulation Programming

- Spent extra time during course learning ancillary skills in various programming languages and environments including Visual Basic 6 & 7, C# 1.0-3.0, and Java 6.
- · Gained experience in Windows system administration in enterprise environments